〔Sound in Water〕
（Durandal）There is no need to hesitate.
If that is your wish,
born from the desired,
the world has desired...
〔Sound of missile launch〕
〔Hatch closing, Mobile Suit activation sound〕
〔Sound of Mobile Suit taking off〕
〔Sound of Mobile Suit flying〕
[Sound of intense gunfire]
[Sound of explosion and screams]
(Arthur) Condition Red has been declared.
Condition Red.
To the Aldrin Autonomous Zone
within the African Republic.
An attacking force, likely Blue Cosmos,
has invaded.
Huh!?
Already!?
(Arthur) Pilots, board your units.
All personnel, commence your assigned tasks promptly.
According to reconnaissance, the invading force
is estimated to have launched from Kanaji city.
Anticipated time of encounter: Next 05:05.
Establish a fixed line with Compass Headquarters
and the Aldrin Autonomous Government.
(Abbie) Operation
Niner 022 proceeding.
Yamato Team, prepare for launch.
Catapult, Alpha Team
from Inductance 20 Futamaru...
(Konoe) The enemy force is estimated
to be squadron-sized. Well, that's the report from the local forces.
It's better to overestimate
in situations like this.
The situation seems urgent.
Understood. After Freedom penetrates,
Shinn will defend the government facilities.
Huh!?
(Kira) Luna Maria and Agnes will
guide the evacuation of civilians while
supporting the Aldrin Defense Force.
Again?
(Agnes) Captain, I'll handle
the frontline enemies. Please join me!
(Shinn) Captain, I'm going too!
(Kira) No, I don't want to
escalate the battlefield.
Harken Team,
we're counting on Millennium.
You got it, Captain!
(Abbie) Catapult connected.
All systems online.
Runway clear.
No obstacles on the course.
Anti-air surveillance team is sharing
airspace monitoring data on Channel D2.
Red Team, evacuation complete.
Gelgoog, you're clear for launch.
Luna Maria Hawk,
Gelgoog, let's go!
(Abbie) Gyan, you're clear for launch.
Agnes Gibenlaat,
Gyan, taking off!
(Abbie) Justice, you're clear for launch.
Shinn Asuka,
Justice, heading out!
(Abbie) Next up,
Freedom, you're clear for launch.
Kira Yamato,
Freedom, heading out!
♪I don't want to lose desire
♪I don't want to lose my fire
♪It's time to countdown the fighting
♪Just one way to freedom
♪Freedom
[♪ Takanori Nishikawa with Tetsuya Komuro "FREEDOM"]
♪Toki o kirisai te jiyū o tsukamae te
♪Te no hira ni tsukanda
♪Tōi sora o nagame te iru mirai o miru wake ja nai
♪Nando mo heiwa no rinen o dareka ni toikakete mi taku te
(Kira) This is
World Peacekeeping Organization Compass.
To the attacking forces,
cease combat immediately.
♪Tenbin no yō kasukana yure risei o kakimidasu
♪Kimi no Resistance, boku to no Distance
Another one...
Ugh!
♪Tōku hanare sugi te
♪ Supported by pure smiles
The wind of those days when we raced through
Argh!
(Shinn) Agnes, provide cover! Argh!
(Agnes) What are you saying?
My unit is for close combat.
You're the one for cover!
♪ With unconditional love deep in our hearts
♪ Even with believing feelings, they spill away like sand
♪ Freedom
Damn it, there's no chance...
Hmph...
(Blue Cosmos Commander) Retreat!
Lower the front lines and regroup in Kanaji city.
(Aldrin Military Staff) We've received word
from Aldrin Defense Headquarters.
Behind this battle is Miquel.
Seize Kanaji and drag Miquel out.
What did you say!?
Seriously?
(Kira) I warn you,
cease your advance!
Colonel Miquel
is not here!
Continuing this battle
will harm the civilians.
If the situation changes, then...
But no one chooses.
People forget and then repeat...
Ugh... Damn it!
(Soldiers) Ah!
Fall back!
They're Milán's enemies!
Why don't you get it?!
[Sound of beam discharge]
[Sound of linear cannon firing]
(Shinn) Captain...
Indeed, Shinn's
on a different level.
[Rough breathing]
(Rescue Team) CP from 734, there are
numerous individuals in need of rescue in the northern residential area of the city, transfer to the civic hospital.
(CP) CP from 734, the civic hospital cannot accept any more due to the disaster, await the establishment of temporary shelters.
(Rescue Team) This is 312, the fire is severe and uncontrollable, requesting the fire brigade.
(Rescue Team) CP from 165, due to the collapse of the bridge, fire trucks cannot pass.
Admiral Kira Yamato,
permission to board for four.
(Murrue) Permission granted. Well done.
(Mu) Hmm. All systems
seem fine, no major issues.
How about it?
Are you getting used to the new model?
(Lunamaria) Yes.
(Shinn) Yeah, well...
(Kira) What's the situation of casualties?
(Murrue) Currently, there are
257 dead, including 68 civilians.
It's probably going to increase.
Hmm...
Once again, no mothership
just a surprise attack with the MS mobile suit force.
It's Miquel's network, right?
(Murrue) But his participation is a fake.
The aim is to make ZAFT violate the border.
He's confident he can lure them out
by using his own name as bait.
Dom, Auel, and Rayha
It's the same trick every time.
(Kira) Yeah...
(Shinn) How long are they
going to keep this up!?
(Shinn) Planning a mission
without expecting a return...
Neither the pilots
nor the units can handle it.
(Mu, Murrue) Mm...
(Kira) But it continues...
Ugh...
That's why it's a problem.
(Mu) It's a deep-rooted problem, actually...
(Narration) Cosmic Era 73.
The new battle between Earth and the PLANTs, which began with Break the World, has finally come to an end, evolving in various ways along the way.
The Destiny Plan, proposed as a new world system, was also buried with the death of Durandal, the chairman of the council who advocated for it.
Everything was left behind, and what remained was deep sadness and confusion.
(Jagannath) President Clyne, are you not aware of the damage to our forces?
It was we who suffered from the unilateral invasion of Blue Cosmos!
If you consider the feelings of the soldiers,
Captain Yamato's actions are too merciless.
It was us who suffered from Blue Cosmos' unilateral invasion!
Considering the soldiers' feelings,
Captain Yamato's actions are too merciless.
(Narration) The gap between Naturals and Coordinators
remains unfilled.
In addition to the independence movements that occurred in various places,
Blue Cosmos, led by Colonel Mikel, repeatedly engaged in guerrilla warfare,
and the conflicts and hatreds continued to smolder in various places.
Concerned about the situation, PLANTs, Orb,
and leaders of the Atlantic Federation
established the World Peace Monitoring Organization, Compass,
and invited Lacus Clyne as its first president.
(Lacus) Chairman Ramtas,
I apologize for causing you concern.
(Ramtas) No...
But Jagannath and others
have no choice but to be harsh.
I've heard that frustration within the military
is growing.
Yes...
As long as Compass remains at the forefront,
there shouldn't be any outbursts.
But there are limits to that too.
Even though we understand that holding onto hatred
is foolish,
we too can be ruled by emotions.
Because what we lost
was too great.
Yes...
In the end, what about Mikel in Kanaji?
(Ramtas) So, his hiding place is
likely the Eurasian military buffer zone...
That's the most probable...
(Ramtas) Hmm...
Even though we know that much,
we're unable to act, given our current situation.
(Lacus) Yes...
(Ramtas) It's been about a month since
the Millennium returned, right?
Can the Vice Admiral take a bit of
a break this time?
(Lacus) Yes, that's the plan.
(Ramtas) That's good to hear.
(Blue) Blue
(Ramtas) However,
though I've met him several times,
he's a mysterious man,
Captain Yamato.
He gives off a quiet impression,
quite unlike someone suited for the battlefield.
But now, it seems he's trying to bear
the contradictions of this war alone.
He's gentle, you see...
I see.
(Lacus Monologue) That's why, quickly,
we must set him free.
Before kindness breaks him...
(Jagnanort) Your Excellency Tao's?
Yes, Chairman of the Defense Committee.
Then, here,
(Cagalli) The above is the offer from
Empress Aura of the Foundation.
I think the same has reached
the PLANTs as well.
(Toya) It seems that country has a fairly
precise grasp on Mikael's whereabouts.
I believe there's significance
in cooperating, but...
Indeed, Toya, there are two sides
to every coin.
(Lacus) What's the return, then?
(Cagalli) It's about joining
the COMPASS.
As a trigger to be recognized by
the international community as an independent nation, perhaps?
Perhaps so.
Since its independence,
the Foundation has seen
remarkable development in both
technology and economy,
but its relationship with Eurasia
is not good.
After all, various regions of Eurasia
have been experiencing a storm of independence as a result.
(Toya) It's the "Foundation Shock," right?
(Lacus) Why was such
remarkable recovery possible?
I've heard it's due to the skill
of Prime Minister Orhfe Ram Taos.
Former Chairman Durandal
acknowledged that talent.
Is the President doubting
the Destiny Plan!?
No, it's not quite like that...
We rejected Chairman Durandal's vision of the future.
However, there must be many people
attracted to that possibility.
We cannot deny even those people.
That's true.
And now, by allowing participation in COMPASS,
there is also the possibility of further straining
relations between COMPASS member states and Eurasia.
That's right.
But Orb also owes them for the theft of Freedom
six months ago.
Hmm...
(Kagali) Is Lacus against it?
Ah...
Please, give me a moment to think.
(Kira) Huh!? But Lacus, that's...
No, Kira, it's not because it's wanted.
Huh!?
I also want it.
Ah...
To fight alongside you.
Lacus!
Am I... not trusted after all?
Huh?
No, Captain. Ultimately, I always end up fighting alone.
But, by doing so, we manage to minimize casualties.
That's true, but!
Then what are we here for?
Well...
Captain, you said it back then, right?
That time, you told me
let's fight together...
Yeah...
(Shin) I was moved by those words
and joined the Compass.
So? Are you still hesitating?
It's not like that! It's just that...
I want to be more useful,
or rather, for you, Kira-san...
Shin, you're Justice,
you've been entrusted with that.
Not being trusted... that's...
(Agnes) Trusted?
As if that's even possible.
For someone once called the Freedom Killer.
Freedom Killer?
Oh, you didn't know?
How delightful.
Someone who might shoot you in the back anytime.
If it were me, I wouldn't want them beside me.
Agnes!
Come on, give it up,
Justice.
Even if you have it,
it's just wasted potential.
Back at the academy, both in skills and evaluation,
I was superior, wasn't I?
(Shin) Hmm...
(Lunamaria) Hey, Agnes!
During the war, I always found it strange,
you being a pilot, a Face and all.
But in the end, it was just the right pawn
for Chairman Durandal, wasn't it?
Ugh!
Enough already!
(Male Announcer) "Casualties in the Oldrin District
have reached 428 deaths."
"With this, the casualties from terrorism
by the remaining Blue Cosmos forces exceed 5,000."
(Female Announcer) "Perceiving the situation gravely,
governments of various countries have"
"issued an international arrest warrant for
Colonel Miquel, the mastermind,"
"and are seeking to dismantle the organization,
though his whereabouts remain unconfirmed."
"The remaining forces of Blue Cosmos..."
[Incoming call tone]
Huh? Oh!
Kira?
(Pink Haro) Akandee! (I can't allow that!)
[Haro bouncing sound]
I see. Please don't push yourself too hard.
(Pink Haro) Mito me takunai! (I won't accept that!)
(Albert) The fermion induction method is still not usable.
With obstacles of micrometer size,
errors in the docking sensors are unacceptable.
Can it be resolved, Captain Heinlein?
Sigh... As the designer, I have no choice but to do it myself.
I'm astonished by the incompetence of the development department.
Setting up and adjusting for Freedom will also take time,
and the bug in the autonomous control program is also a headache.
I'll handle the program,
so Captain Heinlein, I'll leave the sensors to you.
I'm sorry, Colonel...
(Konoe) Is everything all right? You're not leaving?
Yes...
Isn't President Klein waiting for you?
But we need to make this usable quickly...
Overwhelming the enemy is the quickest path to resolving the situation.
Is that so...
It's not like that.
But we haven't been able to protect anything...
[Sound of sleeping breath]
Hm...
Huh, Kira!?
Kira?
What's wrong?
Huh!?
Kira!
[Sound of light turning on]
[Sound of footsteps]
[Sound of sleeping breath]
[Sound of light turning on]
[Sound of monitor powering up]
(Durandal) I won't let this happen again. Who can say they won't make this world like this again?
Who can say they won't make this world like this again? Who can say they won't make this world like this again?
Which world do you say, and which world do I show? Which world do we all wish for?
[Sigh]
In the history of mankind, the reason for the never-ending wars has always been our greatest enemy.
Our greatest enemy has always been our own ignorance and desire!
Hmm... Hmm...
Haah...
Hm? Ah...
(Lacus) Ah!
[Sound of motorcycle running]
(Lacus) It seems Colonel Mikel is hiding in Eldoa near the Eurasian border.
It seems he is lurking in Eldoa near the Eurasian border.
Huh?
Foundation's Empress Aura sent a letter expressing her willingness to cooperate in his arrest.
(Kira) What are you planning to do, Lacus?
(Lacus) To be honest, I'm undecided.
What do you think, Kira?
Why do you ask?
Well...
If it can bring about an end, then I have no reason to oppose it.
Huh?
(Kira) In this conflict, the end is not in sight. People don't change easily.
(Pink Haro) You understand, too.
(Kira) You don't know what can be done and what can't.
What I can do is...
Kira...
Someone has to do it.
Someone has to...
(Shinn) But Eurasia hasn't approved of Compass, right?
(Lunamaria) That's why the Chairman himself is accompanying.
There might be political negotiations or something.
Hey, guys, be careful.
There might be ghosts there.
(Shinn) Huh?
(Herbert) It's the Foundation.
They say the Eurasians saw them during the independence movement there.
Kelpies.
Kelpies?
Creatures that dwell in water.
Well, it's just that it's such an enigmatic country, you know?
(Lunamaria) Hey, cut it out.
(Shinn) Creatures...
(Lunamaria) Lieutenant Harken, no sexual harassment!
[Sound of beam being deflected]
(Albert) 20 seconds to atmospheric entry.
Bridge shields up.
All bulkheads sealed.
(Arthur) The ship will now enter the atmosphere.
Transition the bridge to armored mode.
Protocol R2 initiated. All ships prepare for atmospheric entry.
Cooling systems online. Meltdown shields activated.
♪～
It seems that reconstruction is progressing more than expected.
It must be due to exceptionally talented citizens or a competent government.
(Chandra) Millennium
joining on the starboard side.
(Olivia) Maintain vigilance for air and ground threats.
Down sensors online.
No obstacles detected in the descent path
or in water depth data.
Maintain Levitator output at 20. Hold.
[Sound of landing]
Team D, confirm and report water integrity.
[Bird chirping]
Welcome, Your Highness.
I am Orphé Lam Tao, Prime Minister of the Foundation.
We extend our warmest welcome to you.
I am Lacus Clyne, Chairman of Compass.
It's an honor to meet you.
Ah...
Huh?
(Orphé) Finally, we meet.
Lacus Clyne.
Huh?
(Lacus) And you are?
(Orphé) I am your destiny,
the one who will guide the world with you.
Huh?
(Kira) Lacus.
(Lacus) Ah!
(Orphé) Hmph.
(Orphé) An annoying one.
(Kira's Monologue) What?
[Sirens and breaking glass]
[Young people panicking]
[Gunshots and screams]
(Aura) Welcome to the Foundation.
I am Aura Mah-Hybar.
This time, the Compass's swift response is greatly appreciated.
I am truly honored to receive your audience, Your Majesty Aura.
We are also greatly troubled by the partisans of Míchel in our country.
We have made several appeals to Eurasia,
but it seems that they are taking time to respond.
There is no choice.
They have many internal problems to deal with.
(Aura) I am grateful to you. Please protect our people.
Your words are too kind. I will do my utmost.
I have prepared a modest reception for us to converse.
Please, take your time and share your stories there.
Ah...
[Sword clashing sounds]
(Shura) Huh! Shh! Hmph!
(Ingrit) They are our country's Imperial Guards.
Are they the rumored Black Knights...?
[Sword clashing sounds]
Huh! Hmph!
Huh! Tch! Hmph!
(Shura) Hmph!
[Kira and others panicking]
Well, well...
Can't beat Shura, huh?
Could you give me some pointers, Captain Yamato?
(Shin, Lunamaria) Huh!?
(Kira) No, I...
Oh, the captain can't use a sword, huh?
(Lidell) Maybe being in the Compass isn't all that great after all?
(Daniel) We proved that the other day.
You're being rude to our guests, you two!
Hmph. Captain, let me handle this!
Shin!
Let me try.
Huh?
Commander of the Imperial Guards, Shura Serpentine.
Shin Asuka of the Yamato Squad!
Hmph! Guh! Ngh!
[Shin's spirited shout and the sound of swords cutting through the air]
Shin...
Huh!?
Guh!
Hah!
[Intense sound of swordfighting]
(Kira and others) Ah!
Huh!?
(Lidell) Hu~
(Ryu) Huh
Guh...
(Griffin) What's this? The Freedom Killer isn't all that impressive, huh?
You held up pretty well, didn't you? Kyahahaha!
As expected, Aslan Zara is the strongest.
Huh!? Who's that...?
(Kira) Stop it, Shin!
Captain Serpentine, please stop this nonsense!
Only the powerful rule the world. Do you have that power?
Huh!?
People don't want a world like that!
Huh, do they?
I'm looking forward to fighting under your command.
(Agnes) You're really pathetic, aren't you?
If it's like this, I should have gone instead.
(Lunamaria) Stop it, Agnes!
Agnes Gibbonraat?
Moonlight Valkyrie?
Huh?
Yes...
The strong are beautiful.
(Lacus) We've long heard of your country's prosperity.
(Aura) Our nation employs talented individuals regardless of age or background.
We no longer discriminate against Natural Coordinators.
It's all orchestrated by Orpheus.
[Sound of footsteps]
May I request a song, Your Highness?
Ah...
Certainly...
♪～
But seriously, for such kids to be with those Black Knights...
What are they, those guys?
Coordinators, aren't they?
Probably, but...
Huh? Something up?
They don't seem like a proper military force, that's all.
(Agnes) Won't you dance? Captain.
We didn't come here to play around.
Ah...
[Sighs]
Just stop it. Don't provoke the captain anymore.
Why not? What's wrong with that?
But are you really into him? That person.
I won't compromise at just any place.
Unlike you.
What are you talking about?
It's nothing!
Come on, let's go!
Huh?
Phew...
Hm!?
(Orpheus) Even such splendid flowers,
It seems they don't reflect in your eyes at all.
Ah...
They bloomed for you.
Please.
Thank you. They're very beautiful.
(Orpheus) I'm glad.
If you hadn't liked them,
All the roses would have been disappointed and withered.
Hehe.
They smell nice.
Indeed, a smile suits you.
Ah...
I understand your worries too.
Huh?
Wouldn't everyone agree?
Those living in the present, those seeking paths to the future,
None wish for conflict. However, conflict persists.
Coordinators and Naturals are both human after all.
It's sad. People find reasons to fight over trivial matters.
(Lacus) Yes...
But I believe this: It's not the trivial differences that are the problem,
It's the unjust society that is the real issue.
Huh?
Now, everyone is haunted by the specter of war.
During such times, grievances manifest in ugly ways.
Ah...
(Orpheus) Because of unfair wealth distribution, because lives aren't equally valued,
Because it's not a society where everyone is fairly evaluated, people fight.
If society could present a place where everyone is needed, a fair and equal society,
Overcoming the differences between Coordinators and Naturals,
The world will surely move towards a better direction...
That's what I believe.
That's a wonderful thought. Indeed, it might be so.
To hear you say that, Princess, gives me confidence as one who bears the responsibility of governance.
Ah...
I want to create a world without poverty or discrimination.
That's why I was born,
And you too...
Ah...
Huh...
I apologize, Lord Orpheus. It seems I'm feeling a bit tired from the journey.
With this, I'll take my leave.
Thank you very much for your excessive hospitality today.
Sigh
(Agnes) I've brought some supper for you.
(Kira) Thanks. Just leave it there.
Huh? What's wrong?
(Agnes) I feel sorry for the captain...
He's dancing around with other men in front of everyone,
Even though he's heading to a dangerous battlefield soon...
(Kira) Well, both of those are his job.
(Agnes) Why aren't you angry!?
She's taking advantage of the captain's kindness, isn't she?
Look at me! You want to get back at her, don't you?
What...
What are you trying to do!
Why do you like someone like that?
I wouldn't do that. I wouldn't send the person I love to the battlefield
while I stay safe and just watch.
(Kira) That's not what it's about!
(Agnes) Huh...
You don't understand anything!
Ugh...
Huh?
Ah...
Tao... Your Excellency...
It's a good moon. In the darkness, it equally brings peace, the supreme light.
Don't you think so?
I'm sorry, perhaps another day.
Do you have the right to pursue her?
Huh...
Forgive me, but you are not worthy of her.
Destruction, hatred, and death. Those are the things you create.
Isn't that right?
Huh...
By defeating Chairman Durandal, what did you take from the world?
Order, peace, a society without conflict.
Can you say that you are working to compensate for what people have lost?
What...
The world presented with the Destiny Plan can never go back.
You understand that too, right?
Everyone wants to decide what they can do and what is desired.
She is the guiding light for such a world.
Standing beside her is someone who also guides the world.
Hmm...
I can do it.
Huh...
A world she desires, without the chain of battles.
Creating a world of stability and harmony is what I can do!
That's impossible...
You can't do it. You can only fight.
I...
What will you do when peace comes, with those bloodstained hands?
Are you planning to take her hand with those blood-stained hands?
Urgh...
(Shura) Huh!?
Who's there!?
[Crying]
Hey, am I not pretty? Am I not charming?
Why am I not good enough?
You are beautiful, Valkyrie of Moonlight.
[Sobbing]
[Sigh]
Shin's an idiot, a brat...
(Orpheus) Can't sleep?
Lord Orpheus.
(Orpheus) Please, think of me as nothing more than a shadow cast by the moon.
(Lacus) How can we end all of this?
Huh?
Why is it so difficult for everyone to live without fighting and forgiving each other?
Huh...
We can end it. We can.
Ah.
I am here to help you, only for that reason.
Who are you?
I am Orphé Lam Tao.
I am the one who, together with you, can restore peace to this world.
Ah...
Is that so? But...
I was born for that purpose.
To fulfill the mission given to me.
And so are you.
[Sobbing]
(Aura) Come, children, to a new future.
As your destinies dictate, as everything was predetermined from the beginning.
The world awaits you.
(General) We have obtained details about the Blue Cosmos guerrillas our country has seized.
Mikhail has occupied the Eldora Fortress ruins.
Through underground tunnels, he has confirmed access to Eurasian territory.
There may also be something on the Foundation's side.
That seems to be the case.
Then, while prioritizing the evacuation guidance of civilians, the Foundation's military will contain the enemy group.
The objective is the arrest and restraint of Colonel Mikhail.
We will urge surrender to the Blue Cosmos combatants, minimizing loss of life.
The front-line command will be handled by the Archangel.
(General) The Blue Cosmos shall not set foot within our borders.
But the same applies to the Compass. Access is restricted to the Eldora district only.
(Lacus) Understood.
(General) If they cross the military demarcation line, it will be considered an act of aggression and we will attack immediately.
Whether it's Compass or Foundation.
[Missile launch sound]
[Alert sound] (Chandra) Multiple heat sources approaching, more than thirty!
Helldart, Wombat, Eagle Stern, commence interception!
[Missile launch, machine gun fire sound]
(Kira) Shin, Agnes, Hilda will neutralize enemy MS. We're heading for Mikhail's command center.
Here's the plan.
(Shin and others) Understood!
(Mu) Shikishima team, support Justice Gundam. Mahoroba team, follow me!
[Intense gunfire, missile launch sound]
[Beam firing, explosion sound]
[Alert sound]
(Kira) Get down!
[Agni cannon firing sound]
There's more of that!
(Resident) Help us! Ahh!
[Crowd noise]
Huh?
[Explosion]
Ahh!
[Explosions happening throughout the city]
(Kira and others) Huh!?
(Orphe) How despicable!
(Shula) Vehicles and infantry units, fall back!
(Griffin) What the hell are they doing!
Argh!
You!
(Orphe) Immediately dispatch rescue teams to attend to the wounded in the Eldora city area!
Is that okay?
It's unavoidable. Rescue operations are permitted only in the Eldora district.
Hmph...
Understood.
Initiate the operation.
Yeah, leave it to us.
Roger.
Let's go!
Fall into darkness, Kira Yamato.
Ugh!?
Hah!
Ugh...
Captain?
Hm?
Mikhail?
Hmph
[Missile launch sound]
[Beam firing, explosion sound]
(Shin) Captain, what's wrong!?
Secure Mikhail. Shin, provide cover!
Huh? But...
(Kira) He's getting away!
(Mu) What's wrong, Kira? You're getting close to the border. What are you doing!
(Himeko) Yamato team leader's aircraft is heading towards Charlie at 10-5.
Heading into Eurasian territory.
What did you say!?
What's going on, Ki...
Yamato team leader!
(Kira) Mikhail spotted. Capturing him!
Huh!?
Colonel Flagga, report the situation!
(Soldier) Freedom is nearing the military border!
(General) What's going on? Didn't he know about the pre-negotiations!
(Commander) Warning, Freedom. Your aircraft is approaching Eurasian Federation territory.
Change course immediately!
(Orphe) Why to Eurasia...
(General) What's happening, Chairman!
(Lacus) Freedom, please turn back immediately, Kira!
(General) Warning shots, commence! (Lacus) Please wait!
[Linear cannon, vulcan, beam firing sound]
Still resisting, are they!
(Shin) Captain! (Mu) Kira, stop!
(Murrue) No, Kira!
End it here!
[Full burst firing sound]
This is a clear act of aggression!
Kira, Kira! Can't you hear us!?
(Kira) It's Mikhail. I can't let him escape here!
Ngh...
(Orphe) This is not our intention. It's Captain Yamato acting on his own!
He must have planned to lure in the Compass from the start!
If that's the case, then we'll also take countermeasures!
So it has come to this, Princess!
Please wait. There must be a reason for this.
Captain Yamato...
He's clearly suffering from delusions or perhaps rebellion.
That's impossible!
Unfortunately, the current situation indicates otherwise.
If the Compass cannot control the situation, then leave it to us!
All our diplomatic efforts will be in vain!
It's counterproductive to have casualties due to the actions of a single individual!
By one person's rampage!
(Rio) Princess Lacus...
Ugh...
Understood...
Please stop Kira...
Huh?
(Orphe) Does that mean you're authorizing an attack on Vice Admiral Yamato?
(Lacus) Yes...
Lacus!?
(Mu) Wait, Chairman Clyne!
[Communication noise]
There's strong radio interference. All communications are cut off.
(Albert) It's jamming by the NJ Dazzler.
This isn't yet operational.
How did they solve the control of quantum spattering!?
This isn't from Eurasia or the Blue Cosmos...
Launch Luna Maria's unit! Prepare for sniper rifle and communication thread!
Well done, Shura. Fulfill your duty.
Understood.
I'll finish it in 2 minutes.
Kahaha! Die!
[Missile launch sound]
[Alert sound] Ah! The Black Knights!?
Guh!
Stop it, why!?
Why? Look around you.
Wha... what's going on?
(Shura) I'll kill you!
Sorry, but Princess Lacus doesn't need you anymore!
Shula...
Hah! Captain?
Shin, what's wrong!?
Don't get in my way!
You don't seem to learn.
I've already proven that you're not worth my time!
Shin! Ugh...
These guys, just as I thought!
It's a trap. Archangel, move forward!
Mars unit, Helbert unit, provide cover for our allies' retreat!
Launch signal flares. We're heading to rescue Kira and the others!
(Daniel)
Password... ah
Huh
(Chandra)
Heat source resembling MS, distance 17,000.
[Zoom sound]
Black Knights?
They're quite far back from the Eurasian army. Why are they there?
(Daniel)
Ah, were we seen?
No problem. We'll handle it from here.
[Electronic countdown]
[Cruise missile launch sound]
(Chandra) Detecting heat sources resembling missiles. Providing optical imaging!
(Mariu) Is that...!?
GLCM Mark 72, cruise tactical nuclear missile, originating from the Eurasian army!
[Trembling Mariu and others]
(Himeko) Two Black Knights units are heading towards the main ship!
No way!
Is that...!?
[Reports flying around]
It's from our homeland...
Tactical nuclear missile launch confirmed from within Eurasian territory.
(Lacus and others) Huh!?
What's the target!?
(Commander) Here.
Send an emergency communication to the Millennium!
No use. Still unable to communicate!
[Alert sound]
(Chandra) The main ship has been locked!
[Beam firing sound, explosion]
(Chandra) Godfrey 1 and 2 are hit!
Engage in anti-air combat! Shoot down the Wombat with the Eagle Stern!
Damage control initiated!
Sorry, but I'll have to sink you.
It's all the same, isn't it? Such a hassle.
[Machine gun strafing, missile launch sound]
(Chandra) Eagle Stern, Helderth, unusable!
(Himeko) Multiple heat sources resembling missiles, rapidly approaching!
Deploy flares! Full speed ahead!
The beams aren't working!?
Is this the rumored FemTech armor!?
That's right. If you see it, you're dead!
Battlefield coordinates 020 Whiskey, 138 18 November.
Roger.
(Luna Maria monologue) What's going on, Shin...
(Commander) Friendly fire? Can it be dismissed as friendly fire! It's nuclear! Who the hell...
No use. It won't accept our control!
(Soldier) Major, direct communication from the Foundation Palace!
(Commander) Connect!
[Beam firing, explosion]
All personnel evacuate! Issue emergency evacuation orders to the entire city!
Evacuate residents underground if possible!
Please come this way.
But...
(Ingrit) Hurry!
(Konoe) Bridge closing, rapid dive!
(Arthur) Got it! Vent open, Millennium, rapid dive!
[Submersion sound]
[Cruise missile flight sound]
[Sight sound]
There it is...
Huh...
Ha...
[Relieved crew]
[Cruise missile flight sound]
[Alert sound]
The second one changed course!?
What!?
Evacuate, Luna Maria, we can't shoot this down!
You won't know until you try!
[Alarm sound]
(Orphe) Prepare to depart as soon as ready!
[Engine ignition sound]
[Gate opening sound]
[Cruise missile flight sound]
Go!
[Beam, linear cannon firing sound]
[Alert sound]
Ugh!
[Splash sound]
[Intense explosion sound]
[Intense blast sound]
[Intense explosion and rumbling sound]
[Alert sound]
(Crew) Ugh...!
(Kira) Ugh!
(Shura) Huh
What are these guys...
Damn it to Foundation machines!
(Chandra) Gottfried, Eagle Stern is completely destroyed!
Engines stopped!
The flames are approaching the ammunition depot!
Detach the engines!
Abandon the ship, all hands evacuate!
All hands, evacuate! Ugh!
Prepare for impact!
[Impact sound]
Doing whatever they want in
your absence, big sis!
(Helbert) Tch, this is the monster...
(Mars) Sorry, big sis!
Mars! Helbert!
[Electronic countdown sound]
[Cruise missile, beam firing sound]
Hah!
[Operational sound]
[Beam firing, explosion sound]
[Beam firing sound]
You guys!
Damn it!
Looks like it's the time limit.
Finally...
(Shin) The Archangel is!?
Don't be distracted!
Whoa!
(Hilda) Hold on, boys!
Tch...
[Alert sound]
(Shura) You can't win!
What!?
Because that's your destiny!
[Stinger rapid fire sound]
That one's mine!
Hah! Agnes!?
[Alert sound]
What!?
[Missile, beam firing sound]
Interesting.
Let's do it!
I can!
Kira!
Athrun?
[MS landing sound]
Hah...
(Mu) Sorry, kept you waiting!
Took you long enough...
Athrun Zala?
[Ragged breath]
Shura, it's time!
(Shura) Are you coming?
I'm going, with you!
Agnes, why...
Let's get out of here, Kira!
The people from the Archangel are with us too!
[Cruise missile flying sound]
[Intense explosion]
Ah...
No way...
Huh?
Hmph.
[Sobbing]
Kira...
(Female Announcer) "Four days after the tragedy in Eldoa,
radiation levels on-site remain high."
"Relief efforts from major nations involved
have not progressed as hoped."
"With the NJC facility back in operation,
nightmares have once again erupted on the surface."
"The world trembles, and voices of protest
are growing louder day by day."
(Tohya) "We have confirmed wreckage
thought to be from the Archangel"
"at 1.5 kilometers east of the second ground zero."
"Freedom, Justice, and other MS units
engaged in operations have yet to be found."
"There has been no response
to our calls for them."
"All presumed to have been
caught in the explosion..."
(Lament) "So, President Klein is safe then?"
(Kagali) "Yes,
according to reports from the Millennium."
Have you contacted the PLANTs?
(Lament) No...
What are you going to do about it!
We've received strong protests from Eurasia.
It's all because Captain Yamato violated the agreement
by crossing the military boundary.
But that doesn't justify firing a nuclear weapon.
That would be an act of betrayal
against all humanity.
I can't accept Captain Yamato's actions either.
There are too many mysteries according to the reports.
I have no idea what happened!
The truth is shrouded in darkness.
As long as Captain Yamato or Mikael remain silent
while they're alive...
It's convenient, isn't it?
No one can be held accountable.
What are you trying to say?
(Foster) We're really asking whether Captain Yamato acted on his own
or not, you see.
This incident provides a perfect opportunity
for the PLANTs to intervene in Eurasian territory...
Please stop with these baseless accusations!
Kiracould never do such a thing!
Lady Cagalli...
(Foster) I see...
Then our country has no intention
of further involvement with the Compass.
(Lament) Neither do we. We're tired
of having our insides probed like this.
[Communication interruption sound]
(Cagalli) Huh...
[Sigh]
I can't accept it.
Why hasn't he come back?
Shinn is such an idiot!
(Konoe) I see. So, it's true
that the Foundation...
(Albert) Given the timing of the jamming,
there's a 92% chance it's Black's doing.
It's the Black Knights' work.
It's the Black Knights' doing.
Ah, black, just like the Black Knights... Wait, what!?
So, are you saying that the Foundation
was behind that nuclear attack!?
Ah! Mmgh...
But we have no means
to prove that.
(Albert) The Millennium has been ordered to return,
we have zero mobile suits available.
The Archangel has been shot down too,
the crew's survival is hopeless.
I wonder...
Will they die so easily? Those people?
(Female announcer) "Foundation,
including the Eldoa region, 50,000 dead."
"Injured and missing
estimated to be over 100,000."
"Eurasian forces are preparing for retaliation."
[Sound of opening and closing door]
"All troops are on standby..."
[Sound of turning off the monitor]
Are you both done?
(Shin) Uh, yes.
[Sound of turning on the monitor]
"Mama!"
(Female announcer) "Compass's activities
have already been frozen for the time being..."
[Sound of turning off the monitor]
Huh!?
Is it true
that Compass's activities are frozen!?
Yes, Cagalli seems to have tried her best,
but right now, criticism from around the world is intense.
(Shin) Those guys... Damn!
(Asuran) The only thing left is the Millennium.
現在 オーブに入港している
We haven't informed them of our situation.
What about Lacus...?
It seems she escaped on a Foundation shuttle...
(Kira) She... she betrayed us.
(Asuran) We found something concerning in the terminal investigation.
(Marieu) This... is Empress Aura?
This is her from 19 years ago, when she was at the Mendel Genetic Research Institute.
19 years ago!?
Her research theme was...
...to create a species surpassing Coordinators.
(All) What!?
(Control Officer) Deflection Ring 1, 3, and 6
deployed to target locations as planned.
Target alignment correction plus 2.3.
Requiem launch countdown at
T-minus 60 minutes. System operating normally.
(Asuran) It's likely everything was part of Aura's and their plan.
Including the nuclear attack...
What!?
At least they have an excuse now for launching the nukes.
Requiem, ready for launch.
(Orphe) May God bless us.
[Sound of Requiem launching]
(Asuran) They now have the pretext
to strike Eurasia.
[Sound of a clock chiming]
[Sound of Requiem firing, destruction, explosion]
[Sound of a door opening]
(Toya) Lady Cagalli!
Hmm?
(Erika) Lieutenant Zala,
come to the control room immediately!
(Konoa) Gather information!
Establish communication lines with
the Compass headquarters and Orb government!
(Erika) Moscow...
Is this the Foundation's retaliation... already?
(Shin) A nuclear... attack?
No, this is...
It's Requiem...
(Eurasian Federation Representative) Wasn't Requiem
supposed to be dismantled!?
(East Asian Republic Representative) This is a blatant violation
of the ceasefire agreement by PLANT!
(Eurasian Federation Representative) We absolutely cannot
tolerate such retaliation!
(Foster's Secretary) Mr. President...
(Foster) What do you mean? Connect me immediately!
[Electronic sound]
"We have been driven from the surface."
"By the hateful nuclear
weapon unleashed by Naturals,"
"Our desires for peace and stability
have once again been trampled by the stubborn Naturals."
"Why!?"
"Our nation, as a national policy,
accepted the Destiny Plan proposed by former PLANT Supreme Council Chairman,"
"Mr. Gilbert Durandal."
"A society completely just and equal
through genetic manipulation,"
"Accepting our roles engraved in our genes,
we overcame poverty,"
"And achieved miraculous reconstruction
after the previous war."
"But lazy humans
are not pleased with that!"
"They deny evolution,
envy others, and hold onto past grudges,"
"Killing each other in their
ugly emotions."
"While living on the peaceful land of Earth,
they are like parasites consuming its benefits greedily!"
"We ask!"
"Why must we walk together
with such ignorant fools?"
"Coordiantors living on PLANT,"
"We are your brothers."
"We, like you, are the beings
to inherit the future of human evolution!"
"We are the ultimate Coordinators
created through genetic manipulation."
"We, like you, are beings who will inherit
the future of human evolution!"
"We are also the ultimate Coordinators
created through genetic manipulation."
"We are the 'Accords'!"
"The role engraved in our genes
is to guide the world as mediators of humanity."
"We were born for that purpose."
"One of your leaders,"
"President Lacus Clyne, is also one of us!"
"She is now with us as a leader
who guides humanity."
"Our will is her will,
and our desires are her desires!"
"Let's go together,
brothers of the Coordinators!"
"The era of contradictions and tyranny
by the old humanity has ended."
"This is a notice to all nations of Earth."
"Immediately disarm and
approve and execute the Destiny Plan!"
"The deadline is 5 days."
"For those forces unwilling to accept us,
under the name of Lacus Clyne,"
"sanctions will be imposed by Requiem."
"The fires of Armageddon
will rain down upon them..."
What is this...
(Asuran) Kira!
(ZAFT Soldier) Chairman to the bridge!
(Lament) Mrs. Jule Canaar, former representative, you are safe.
However, domestic turmoil may require us
to remain passive for the time being.
Understood, Chairman.
In the worst-case scenario, Requiem's targeting
may once again be directed towards the PLANTs.
(Lament) For now, we must assess the situation
and remain in hiding.
What are the arrangements for that?
It's difficult to say we are fully prepared.
There is a supply facility for the resistance entrusted by Lady Lacus located in the abandoned Boaz.
(Diarka) We will go there...
(Lament) Hmm... understood.
I apologize for keeping you waiting alone for so long, Your Highness.
If you can apologize.
Please let me return as soon as possible if you can apologize.
Return?
Your rightful place is here.
(Aura) That is also your mother's will.
Huh?
Mother's?
(Asuran) The Destiny Plan selects people by genetics...
...and assigns roles based on aptitude.
Durandal and Aura...
...oversee this system and created leaders to guide the people.
That's the Accord.
What!?
(Aura) You were born for the people.
To be loved by all and to show them the way.
Huh?
That's how I created you.
Me... created!?
(Asuran) And the key figures of the Accord are Orpheus Ram Tao...
...and Lacus...
(All) Huh!?
Lacus!?
(Aura) The two of you should stand at the pinnacle of all humanity, the final pair of pieces to be combined.
These are the last pieces that will be joined together.
(Orpheus) You and I will rule this world together.
Do you feel it? [Resonance sound]
Together... with you?
We are drawn to each other and bound by fate.
(Asuran) That's why they took Lacus.
Because she was necessary for their plan.
(Kira) Lacus!
Huh!? Ugh...
The one I love is not you!
Ugh! Hmph...
Are you concerned about Kira Yamato?
Unfortunately, he is no longer in this world.
Huh!?
(Orpheus) You were told you could strike him down, weren't you?
[Sobbing]
Kira!
Anyway, he is no longer necessary...
In the world to come.
(Lacus) Because I'm needed...
Because I'm needed, it's not out of love!
I'm needed because I love you!
Huh?
Stop with the nonsensical Natural-like words!
Launch!
Shura, Ingrit, I'm counting on you to protect Mother and the princess!
(Asuran) According to the information, there's currently a military coup underway in the PLANTs.
Details are unclear, but we've lost contact with the chairwoman and other council members.
(Shin) What!?
But we're stuck here with no means of action—no mobile suits, no ships.
So basically, we're all sitting ducks here...
It's speculative, but it seems the Accord can read our minds.
(Shin) What!?
(Asuran) Probably...
They might be able to influence our minds.
Is that why the captain...?
(Female Announcer) "Following total surrender to Earth's nations, the Foundation advises disarmament and the execution of the Destiny Plan."
"If this advice is not followed, they will immediately launch Requiem."
"If this advice is not followed, Requiem will be launched immediately."
"In that case, further statements warn that civilian evacuation will not be permitted."
[Sound of a shower]
(Asuran) Let's rescue Lacus. That's the only way...
To break through this situation and stop the PLANTs, we need her words.
It's useless.
(All) Huh?
(Marieu) Kirakun?
It's all the same anyway...
No matter what we do...
(Search Soldier) ZAFT fleet detected. Our fleet is deploying to the right flank, left flank, and front.
(Communications Soldier) The left flank of the fleet has been fired upon!
Each ship, evasive maneuvers to the right! We're being fired upon on the right flank too!
[Sound of ship gunfire]
(Commander) Don't cluster together, or we'll take a direct hit from Requiem!
[Sound of Requiem firing, explosion]
(Kira) In the end, it's all repeating. After all that suffering, hesitation, fighting...
Fighting, fighting!
But nothing changes...
Is it because I'm wrong!?
Kira...
That's why Lacus chose him over me!
I'm no good!
I can't give her anything she wants!
I can't even make her smile!
I can't make her happy! That's why she betrayed me!
Hmph!
[Sound of a punch]
(All) Ahh!
Stop your useless whining!
It's always about you, you, you!
You never think about her feelings at all!
Enough! If you hate fighting so much, then just stay here and rot!
You don't understand anything... I don't want to hear that from you!
Nngh!
Whoa!
Ugh!
Do you think you're the only one fighting!?
It can't be helped, can it? Because you're weak!
Don't mess with me!
So if things don't go your way, you just give up on carrying the weight of the world alone!?
Some hero you are!
What a joke!
No!
Whoa!
Ugh!
Stop it, Athrun! The captain...
Sound of punching
Gah!
Damn it!
Just let it happen.
Fixing up a pathetic guy like you is what friends are for.
Ugh... Grrrr!
I'll do it!
I have to do it!
Even if I hate it, I'll do it desperately!
Why don't you say it, ask for it, from someone!
What can you do alone!?
Sound of punching
Gwaaah!
Aah!
Hah, hah
(Kira) I want to see Lacus...
Huh?
Lacus...
I just want her to be next to me, smiling...
I don't know anymore
what I should do!
(Athrun) Lacus has changed a lot
since we last met.
Huh?
Thinking you can't be happy or do anything
unless you do things like this.
Ah...
(Athrun) The Lacus I know
wouldn't say things like that.
(Everyone) Huh!?
(Everyone) Ah...
Lacus wanted the world
to be at peace.
But she didn't think someone could just
give peace to her as a gift, right?
Wasn't she looking for someone
to walk towards that with her?
Someone to walk together with, towards that goal?
Even if it's one step at a time,
even if it's small...
Does she still feel that way now?
Lacus...
If you're worried, go and ask her in person.
Huh?
Let's go, Kira.
Let's save Lacus.
Together.
Because there are things that can't be conveyed
unless you put them into words.
Yeah!
(Meer) Analyzing the trajectory,
We've narrowed down the area where the
Foundation's shuttle is headed.
Combined with Orb's information,
Lacus is probably...
It's troublesome, the Artemis Fortress...
If we use the Triton and Blue's quantum network,
we can pinpoint Lacus's location.
Once we get close enough,
we'll know her whereabouts, right?
But only if Lacus still has it with her...
(Shin) What about the ship?
We don't even have MS that can fight properly.
We might be able to procure a ship,
although it might be a bit rough.
As for the MS,
I might be able to manage something.
It was entrusted to me by the Asaha representative,
and it was being used for performance evaluation
experiments on new fusion reactors and equipment.
I didn't anticipate this kind of situation,
Destiny!
Freedom...
(Erika)
The propulsion and armaments are still the same as before,
but the control system has been updated
to the latest version.
It might be uncertain to counter the Black Knights,
(Shin) No, with this, we can take on guys like them!
[Sound of wire being ejected and fixed]
[Sound of wire being reeled in]
Here it comes!
[Electronic sound]
[Alert sound]
Captain, it's an injection attack.
I see...
(Jamie) Crew members,
evacuate the ship immediately.
Repeat, emergency alert, emergency alert,
toxic gas detected on ship's B deck!
What's going on!?
(Maryuu) Don't move!
(Arthur) Ye--s!
My calculations were
off by two minutes, Captain Yamato.
Captain Konoe...?
Preparations for departure are complete,
Colonel Ramius.
Such hazardous things
are not necessary.
(Shin) Don't move...
Put your hands up and drop the gun.
(Lunamaria) Hmph! Take that!
(Shin) Uwah!
[Sound of elbow strike and knee kick]
(Shin) Ugh, guwah!
Ugh...
Ha! Luna, me, me!
Shin!?
Haa, it hurts... Huh?
Shin!
Uwah!
(Lunamaria) Idiot, idiot, seriously!
I thought you were dead!
Oww... I'm going to die... Really going to die...
[Lunamaria sobbing]
(Orphe) The Millennium
has been hijacked?
(Soldier) Yes, there are notices
to the PLANTs and the Atlantic Federation.
Even satellite images show increased movement of people and objects around the dock.
Hmph, Orb, as expected...
(Kira) We'll infiltrate Artemis Fortress
and rescue Lacus.
(Asuran) Using Mirage Colloid
to approach and evade enemy detection.
Nicole's tactics...
(Konoe) We'll break through
the main fleet and head to the moon.
(Maryuu)
We'll be the bait, I see.
(Albert) If they find out who we are,
they'll attack Orb immediately.
Before that, we'll neutralize Requiem.
The Requiem main body is shielded,
making destruction by conventional firepower impossible.
The beam relay points are
camouflaged with Mirage Colloid,
so their location cannot be predicted
until they are launched.
Except for one place, though...
Only the first relay point
is directly above the Requiem's firing line.
Right before launch, for sure!
(Konoe) Then, Captain Ramius.
Huh?
No!
It can't be...
This ship is neither Compass nor ZAFT now.
It's a rebel, a pirate, if you will.
Someone who knows how to fight
like that should sit in this seat.
Understood...
Then, Colonel Konoe,
I entrust you with the position of Vice-Captain.
With pleasure!
Huh? Oh, really?!
(Neumann) All sections checked.
Main engine output increasing.
30 seconds to rated output.
Preparations for departure complete.
(Konoe) Release the mooring ropes.
(Neumann) Water jet engaged.
[Engine ignition sound]
Leaving the harbor, Millennium advancing, first combat speed.
(Aegis Ship Commander) Halt! Millennium, immediately cease your movement!
Failure to comply will result in your ship being attacked.
Maintain course, both sides to second combat speed!
Huh? Wh-What!? But!
(Aegis Ship Commander) Permission to fire! Captain, understood?
Yes!
One hundred shots, all missed, is a tradition of the Todaka Sea Admiral!
Commence firing!
[Main cannon and missile launch interception sound]
[Explosion and impact sound]
Hmph... What a farce.
(Orphe) It seems Orb has chosen to ignore our warning.
What nonsense. There should still be time for a response!
We are currently consulting the parliament regarding your country's demands.
(Orphe) Transparent trickery. We are aware of the movements of the Millennium as well.
In 10 minutes, we will launch the Requiem towards your country.
Wait! The Millennium has been hijacked by someone!
Just a moment ago, in PLANT...
I told them, if there's any movement, shoot!
(Kagali) It's a misunderstanding! We have nothing to do with this...
Sooner or later, you're a country that must be shot at anyway.
Hmph.
(Kagali) Hasten the evacuation of all citizens, and Orb's military must support this with all its might!
Government functions will be relocated to the Onogoro Island air defense facility.
Lady Kagali...
Hurry! We only have 10 minutes!
Engage maximum power, disengage from the water!
Main thrusters, engage!
[Jet sound]
Millennium, launch!
Ah! Captain, oh...
The Foundation!
(Orph)
Prepare to fire the Requiem!
The target is Orb's capital, Orphat.
(Announcement) Citizens, please follow the instructions and evacuate immediately.
I'm counting on you, Tohya.
Lady Kagali... Please take care.
This way, please.
(Miriaria) Representative Asaha!
Strike Rouge, Cavalier Airfreed 2, ready to go! Hurry!
Understood.
Got it.
As I suspected, they won't be fooled!
They intended to attack Orb from the beginning; they just needed an excuse!
(Kagali Monologue) Father, please protect the people... Kira!
Farewell, Orb.
(Kira) Foundation, do you copy?
This is the Minenia, Kira Yamato.
(Communications Officer) Receiving broadcast on the international distress channel.
What!?
Too bad.
I'm still alive.
Even though you tried to kill me by sacrificing your own people.
What's going on, Shura!?
Nonsense... In that situation!?
(Kira) You guys aren't leaders guiding humanity.
You're just murderers!
We know the truth. We have evidence.
We'll expose it to the world.
You've lost!
Whatever Accord or whatever, we'll crush the schemes of the slaughterers!
If I may...
Mother!
Kill that failure!
The target is the Minenia!
Fire! I command it!
High-energy reaction on the far side of the moon!
Activate Tanhauser, emergency braking!
[Tanhauser activation sound]
[Requiem firing sound]
[Explosion sound]
Fire!
[Tanhauser firing, engine thrust sound]
(Search soldier) Lost the Minenia due to electromagnetic pulse!
(Dracus) Damn it!
Inform all units! Henceforth, we will exercise our full strength for the defense of our homeland!
National defense directive issued!
Establish tactical link with Compass Council countries, Minenia Eternal!
The military shall continue evacuation guidance with civilian safety as the top priority.
Even though it's been converted to nuclear power, it's surprising they kept such an old machine.
I like it though. The control system of the Zaku is easy to use.
Isaac Jule, Duel, launch!
Dearka Elsman, Buster, launch!
(Kira) Well then, Maru-san, here I go.
(Maryu) Yes, I'll definitely get Lacus-san.
Yes.
(Kira) Shin.
Ah...
I'm counting on the Minenia.
Huh?
Yes!
Well done, Boz.
Really, you're so simple.
Heh heh.
Was it weird?
No.
Isn't it okay?
Hmm...
(Ingrid) Why...
Yes?
Why does the princess not accept her destiny?
We were given power and were born to fulfill a purpose. Isn't our happiness living according to that and being needed by others?
Doesn't every life have the right to choose its own path?
This isn't the destiny I desired.
Is it the princess's wish for this conflict to continue endlessly?
Is it her desire for everyone to suffer and struggle?
The princess doesn't understand her own fortune!
Even though she could rule the world, why won't she accept Orpheus?
Is that what you want?
You...
Huh?
[Sound of door opening]
Have you cooled your head?
It's about time you realized your own mission and took my hand, isn't it?
No matter how many times you ask, my answer remains the same.
The one I love is not you.
Kira Yamato is dead!
No, he's not dead.
Why won't you accept the truth!
Because I believe in him.
[Sound of falling]
(Orpheus) Why! Why someone like him...
A failed product that couldn't become an Accord!
Because he's the person I decided to love.
He couldn't create anything you wanted, not even a peaceful world!
Does someone like that have the right to be by your side?
Love doesn't have qualifications. Don't you understand?
Even if you control people with power, you can never control their hearts.
No matter what you do, you can't erase Kira from within me.
Why? You were supposed to be born to rule over me and the world!
But why won't you accept me? My love!
The "Lacus Clyne" you love isn't me.
Huh!?
[Sound of door opening]
I'm heading to the moon. I leave the defense here to you and Shula.
Yes.
(Officer) Prime Minister, to the bridge.
(Orpheus) What are the movements of the Millennium and other hostile fleets?
(Officer) The remaining fleets of the Orb Moon Fleet and Earth Alliance are heading towards the Requiem.
They are deploying in the front, and engagement with the ZAFT fleet is anticipated.
The Millennium is heading towards us on the shortest course.
Estimated time until encounter: about 4 minutes.
All fleets, form the CW Kroné Wing formation, reverse, and adjust relative speeds.
Align the twelve-ray positron cannons with the projected course of the enemy ships!
(Mariu) Bridge shield, first combat deployment.
(Konoe) With this formation, our positron cannons won't be usable.
It's okay. We have a new weapon: heat-resistant and shock-resistant crystal armor, deploy!
Execute Basil Rule tactics.
(Albert) Missile timing input completed.
(Mariu) Anti-beam torpedo launch!
Tristan CIWS Sirius activation, missile launch tubes, Nighthard Disparl loading.
Full combat speed, break through the center!
Feuer Fire!
[Missile, beam, and positron cannon firing sounds]
They're not evading!?
(Mariu) Disparl, CIWS!
Start firing!
[Interception, explosion sound]
Can you withstand it?
Of course!
[Beam firing, direct hit, explosion sound]
Well done, scoundrels!
Disperse high-speed anti-ship guided missiles along the enemy's projected course!
All ships, turn around and pursue the enemy at full speed!
High-speed missiles approaching, continue pursuit, enemy fleet turning around!
Fire Disparl, ships turn 180 degrees, left drift, match relative speeds!
All mobile suits, launch!
♪～
(Abby) Catapult connected, all systems online.
Super-electric capacitors, critical levels reached from 1 to 10.
No anomalies detected in the guidance system.
Clear path. Destiny, you're clear for launch.
Shin Asuka, launching Destiny!
(Abby)
Impulse, you're clear for launch.
Lunamaria Hawke, launching Impulse!
(Abby)
Gelgoog, you're clear for launch.
Hilda Harken, launching Gelgoog!
Heading to the combat bridge. Take care of the rest.
(Konoe) Best of luck.
(Jamie) Transitioning the main bridge to combat mode.
(Abby) Guidance systems online. Launch all silhouettes!
(Scout Soldier) Enemy MS launching, three in total.
Intercept! No, wait...
Where's Kira Yamato?
(Scout Soldier) Approaching MS detected, one unit, it's Freedom!
What!?
How did they find us here?
But to come alone to save the princess... How touching, isn't it?
Shura.
Then, it would be foolish to confront them as a group. I will go.
Crush their foolish hopes completely.
(Shura) Understood!
(Kira) Lacus.
Kira!?
(Orphe Monologue) What's this... unsettled feeling...
But to scatter forces recklessly...
Launch MS squad, exterminate the enemy!
Destiny, huh? What a bunch of jokers.
Might be some fun in killing them, huh?
It's just right for soldier training.
(Missile launch, explosion sound)
Don't underestimate us!
I'm in this too!
♪～
This time, none shall escape!
Tsk!
Ah, sudden sound inside the defense line!
I'll handle it.
[Gunshot]
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Close all bulkheads, forcibly!
I don't understand... Why?
(Pink Haro) Mitometakunai! (Red Haro) Here we go!
Lieutenant Kisaka.
(Kisaka) Let's go!
(Haros) Haro Haro Haro Haro (Pink Haro) Honanaa!
(Haros) Haro Haro Haro Haro (Pink Haro) Akandee!
(Navy Haro) Zekkocho!
[Air hissing]
(Control Officer) It's not working. Control has been taken over!
System down!
What are you doing? Call Shura back!
Can't reach them.
Huh?
[Sound of collapsing]
Ugh...
Huh!?
Shura, the enemy has breached.
(Try) Try!
You...
Asran Zala, right?
I thought you could read minds?
Guess not.
I'll kill you!
[♪～ Mika Nakashima, "Boukyou"]
(Ingrit) I can't let you go.
Kiray has come, hasn't he?
What's there to be happy about!?
Because with you there, they have the advantage in battle too.
That's why they risked danger to come and take you.
Is that all?
Is it really?
Even Orpheus loves you because you are outstanding!
That's why he loves you!
Isn't it the same for everyone?
They want something exceptional, something close to them.
Because you have that value, you are needed!
You are loved, right!
Is that truly love?
Huh...? Ah!
Lacus!
Kira!
Ah!?
Don't come!
Even if I move a bit,
I'll crush this person's eyes!
I can slit his throat,
rendering him unable to sing...
Even then,
can you still say you love him!?
Yes, even if those eyes can't see,
even if that voice is lost, Lacus is Lacus!
I love all of that!
Kira...
[Ingrit gasps]
It's not because I need you that I love you.
It's because I love you that I need you!
(Blue) Blue.
Ah!?
Ah!
Ugh!
(Lacus) Kira!
Lacus!
This is reckless!
I love you too...
I'm sorry...
Go!
[Sobbing]
[Explosion]
Ah!
Tch!
Lacus, please take care of yourself. I'm heading to Requiem.
(Asuran) They're strong. Be careful.
Yeah, this time I won't lose. I'm not alone.
Kira, please, be safe.
Yeah!
(Soldier) Deflection Ring 11, moved to First Point.
Fire Requiem! Burn down Orb!
(Soldier) Roger! Requiem firing. Target: Orb capital, Orphat!
Receive the consequences of what you've done, Kira Yamato!
(Soldier) Requiem firing in 10 seconds. 9, 8, 7, 6, 5...
Vertical axis correction. Approaching critical discharge voltage!
(Soldier) MS detected near Requiem firing port!
What!?
Go!
[Explosion]
[Requiem firing sound]
Grrrrrrrr!
(Murrue) Mu!
Phew... Well, making the impossible possible is tough.
[Cheering from the Millennium crew]
Ha...
(Soldier) Primary relay point under attack, disappearing!
(Soldier) Deflection ring installation ship, navigation disabled!
(Soldier) Requiem, outer shell damaged! Beam convergence system damaged!
(Soldier) Heat source approaching Requiem...
(Orphe) Immediately begin recovery!
You old humans!
(Amagi) Disguise released. Objective: seize or completely destroy Requiem! All units, weapons free!
Or complete destruction. All units, weapons free!
Never forgive those who turn their blades toward Orb!
MS teams, evacuate from the firing axis.
Fire the Lohengrin!
[Lohengrin firing sound]
(Murrue) Guidance cannons, separate.
Tristan, number 1, number 2, Kurvénal.
Target: enemy battleship. Fire!
[Linear cannon, beam firing sound]
The Black Knights are coming.
Beams won't work. Luna, provide support!
We have anti-ship swords too. It's me!
You really don't learn, idiots. You can't beat us!
I'll bring you down again. Hahaha!
You can't get near the Millennium!
That MS...
Agnes, why!?
Impulse, Luna Maria!?
Agnes, you're alive!
Only Shura understood my worth!
You're just being used. Don't you understand!?
You're a Coordinator too, aren't you? Why are you siding with them!?
Has some stupid guy's influence messed with your head!?
Huh? Shin has nothing to do with this!
It's you who's not taken seriously by the captain!
Shut up!
Who's this guy!?
Last time, it was Justice that lost!
But if it's Destiny,
you guys won't stand a chance!
Can't read his thoughts!?
Does this guy even think!?
Don't let a single one through. They're just a bunch of Naturals!
(Communications Officer) Hamilton, Schecter, sunk!
Enemy MS approaching!
Damn!
(Communications Soldier) Lieutenant Juggernaut, message from the PLANTs!
Huh?
(Communications Soldier) The Chairman is calling for a halt to all military operations and the suppression of the coup.
What!?
(Radio) CP, this is 506. Targets have surrendered and disarmed.
(Radio) CP, understood. Continue to watch out for IEDs.
(Radio) CP, this is 505...
(Juggernaut) Continue the attack! Once the Requiem fires on Orb...
The era will change!
Ugh...
Damage control!
(Isaac) This is the ZAFT Information Bureau. Lieutenant Isaac Juel speaking.
We are carrying out orders from the military headquarters!
Under the command of Lieutenant Juggernaut, all ZAFT soldiers are to immediately cease combat and return to their original units!
Huh!?
(Asran) Captain Ramias.
(Murrue) Huh?
This is the Millennium. Prepare for broadcast immediately.
Welcome back, Lacus-sama!
Lieutenant Juggernaut, do you wish to be charged with treason!
This is not treason. We are the ones who will bear the future of the PLANTs!
(Lacus) "I am Lacus Clyne."
Ngh...
(Lacus) "I have just escaped confinement by the Foundation."
"I am speaking to all of you."
"Firstly, I do not agree with the Foundation's perspective."
"The fair and equal society they propose is governed by the Destiny Plan."
"As I have stated before, I will not accept it."
"A world where failure, change, and dreams are not allowed..."
"A society that determines human worth by genetics."
"I will not entrust my own worth to others!"
"Let alone force it upon others through violence or fear."
"It is never acceptable!"
"Every life has the freedom to determine its own destiny."
"I will fight for that as well."
"Do not let someone who does not love you ever determine your worth."
Huh!?
We can't let this go on any longer!
Ugh!
We have no purpose if we can't fulfill our duties!
(Soldier) Enemy fleet approaching the Requiem!
Engaging M1A1 Shura and X20A!
Flagship, fleet heading towards the Requiem!
Against the Millennium,
Draw the fleet defense line and annihilate them!
Mother, I entrust the rear to you. Freedom will be dealt with by me and Shura.
Let's go, Ingrid!
This ship will break through the enemy fleet and assault the enemy flagship. It's the decisive battle!
(Lacus) Captain.
Lacus-san?
I will also sortie. Please grant permission.
Huh!?
If I don't deliver this to Kira,
that is what I must do.
(Marieu) But, that's...
(Lacus) Please. Let me go just this once!
(Albert) Chief Instructor, Albert here. The unit can operate at 100% performance, but
manual adjustments are required for docking.
I will guide perfectly, so please don't worry.
Understood. Launch is authorized.
(Lacus) Thank you.
Jeez...
Isn't it fine? Sometimes just watching is much harder than actually doing it, you know.
Cavalier, takeoff.
Asran Zara, Z'Gok, go!
(Abbie) Defender, you're cleared for launch.
Lacus Klein, here I go! Hmph...
You too, prove your own worth!
Understood...
Let's go!
Surrender, Lieutenant Colonel. The coup in our homeland has also failed.
Don't waste soldiers needlessly!
Why side with the inhabitants of the old world!
Nothing will change like this!
A world where a few are wealthy and injustice and tyranny prevail!
Fools stuck in the past!
It's no use, Isaac.
Rather than agreeing to negotiate, they won't do something like this.
Damn it!
Fire!
Pathetic!
What!?
To challenge us with outdated MS!
Strength isn't determined solely by the performance of the MS!
Indeed, that's why you, inferior to us, will never win!
But I have a weapon too!
What's that?
Hmm!?
It's Lacus's love!
[Full burst firing sound]
Don't mess with me!
(Kira) Urgh!
(Orb) Disgusting!
Trash like you speaking Lacus's name...
Even if I kill you a million times, your guilt won't disappear!
Guh...
[Power down sound]
Ah! Shin!
Luna!
Shin!
Fire the Deuterion Beam!
[Energy charging sound]
Persistent...
Ryu, Daniel!
Ah!
It's over, lackey!
You've always been meddling with people's boyfriends, haven't you?
What's wrong with that? If they're men, they should all like me. Don't be jealous!
Why are you getting in the way? You can't do anything, you failure!
Ugh!
(Orb) You shouldn't have been born!
Yet you live comfortably and are loved!
You have no right to do so!
You don't need qualifications to be loved!
Huh!?
Then hand over that love!
She was supposed to be mine! But youuuu!
Ugh...
[Alert sound]
[Power down sound]
It's over, Freedom!
Ah!
Kira!
[Stinger rapid fire sound]
Asuran!
Ugh!
What!?
(Asuran) Are you okay, Kira?
(Kira) Asuran!
(Lacus) Kira!
Lacus!
Docking!
Deliver the finishing blow to Freedom,
Hit it with all firepower!
Relative speed plus 1.2,
Axis correction plus 3, connection.
Engage!
Huh.
Ah...
What!?
[♪~ T.M.Revolution "Meteor-ミーティア-" ♪]
Interesting!
Lacus, why...
My will is with you,
Please take care of me for a while.
It's been a while, please.
Let's go.
Yes!
To go to such lengths to reject me...
Then perish along with that foolish love of yours!
This is what I...
[Multi-lock-on]
[Discharge sound]
What is that weapon!?
Use the Disruptor!
Lieutenant Commander Kira Yamato
Requesting permission to use the Disruptor.
Chairwoman Lacus Clyne
Permission granted to use the Disruptor!
Disruptor activation, 80% output!
The enemy is hiding behind the Messiah,
Linking to my consciousness.
[Disruptor beam discharge, cut-off sound]
(Soldier) Repairs on the Requiem are complete.
The deflection ring is moving to the primary relay point.
Once ready, fire the Orb.
Take out the enemy fleet with it!
It's a synchronized attack.
Let's go!
(Griffin Units) Understood!
Plunge into darkness!
Huh!?
I'll protect Shinn!
[Grotesque sound]
The darkness of this one...
Is too deep!
Whoaaa!
Did he disappear?
Impossible!
Such a sleepy doppelganger
won't work on me!
I've never seen a weapon like this before!
This is how you use a doppelganger!
What!?
Huh!?
They're the ones who did it!
Aaaah!
Lido!
Uwaaa!
No!
Whoaaaa!
(Aura) My children!
Aaaaah...
I'll burn down Orb and the Plants!
Why is it always me who has to suffer!
Why can't things ever go right!?
Are you seriously saying that!?
You're not even into him
But you're still hanging around with that loser
You're really enjoying this, aren't you!
Huh? I like him, sorry!?
Lies! You like that jerk!?
It's none of your business!
If I don't like him, why do you care!
Ugh... Because I
have worth to be loved!
So what!?
[Alert sound]
Even I... care about him...
I'm sorry, Agnes...
Fire the Tanhauser!
[Tanhauser firing sound]
(Mariu) Now! Full speed ahead on both sides!
Enemy ship, main gun range, Bravo, Mark 31 to 65!
Target: enemy flagship!
Crash into it if you have to, bring it down!
Never forget! The blood shed by the dead, their grudges!
Never forget!
Huh!?
I haven't forgotten...
Ah!
That's why, I must stop this now...
You're strong, Aslan Zara.
Ugh...
But still, you're not my enemy.
Winning is the task given to me,
it's the meaning of my existence!
It's futile. You can't
close off your thoughts! Huh?
(Aslan) Kagari!
Ah!
You, indulging in such lascivious fantasies
in this sacred battlefield!
I see!
What!?
Idiot! Why!?
You really are useless.
Remote control!?
Lascivious fantasies?
Aslan!
You coward!
Still, I'm superior!
Strength isn't about power,
it's about the will to live!
I'm going to lose!?
Huh!?
Orpheus, Shura!
Shura...
Damn it, you insects!
Orpheus, Ingrid,
let's stop this now.
You chose that man
because he's inferior to you!
Surrounded by inferior beings,
is it really so pleasant to be worshipped?
Ugh...
(Orpheus)
What a selfish and cold woman!
Are you saying you don't care
if these fools keep fighting and perishing!?
Shin!
Destroy the Requiem!
(Mu)
Bows!
(Shin)
Old man!
(Mu)
I'm not old man!
Take his equipment!
(Shin)
Yes!
(Díaz)
Lunamaria, use that!
Let's go, Luna!
Anytime!
(Soldier)
Millennium is closing in!
Fire! Shoot it down!
Is the Requiem ready!?
(Soldier)
300 seconds until launch!
Charge!
Bow, activate the Gouten ramming device!
All cannons, prepare for close-range loading!
All hands, prepare for impact!
Wow! Aahh!
[Crash sound]
(Lacus)
There is no superiority or inferiority in life.
Everyone is someone important to someone else.
Why then am I not loved!?
No, someone is surely
watching over you.
Even if not now, someone in the future.
Someone who is so close that you don't notice.
Hah!
Forget about the future.
I want you now!
Born out of the foolishness of humanity...
Claiming peace and equality,
yet demanding others to change
While refusing
to change themselves!
That's not true!
That's why conflict persists
throughout history!
Harboring grudges,
even on the brink of destruction,
Clutching onto immediate gains and misconceptions,
dragging each other down!
Everyone is a fool!
Orpheus!
We need someone to lead us!
To end this history of division
and bloodshed...
That's the purpose we were born for!
People are not born out of necessity...
It is born from love!
I will choose the future with my own hands!
Uwaaaa!
Fire!
[All cannons firing simultaneously]
Foolish...
I have a mission...
It's okay now, Orpheus...
Ingrid...?
Because I know...
[♪ See-Saw "Departure Romance"]
♪I'll sing at the end
♪～
♪This red afterimage is the romance of departure
♪Layering books, the record of our rebirth comes to an end
(Lacus)
"The opposite of love is not hatred"
"The opposite of love is indifference"
"I have you within me"
"Do I exist within you?"
"The joy of having you within me"
"The strength of having me within you"
"Whether it's bright or dark, I don't know"
"The future is something unseen"
"But if there are hands to connect, if there are hearts to support each other"
"Even if we can't see each other, we'll move forward"
"For the hands that connect us, to make those hands stronger"
"Let's get to know each other"
"We'll talk"
"The many things in my heart, even the small ones"
"So please, you too, tell me"
"The many small things in your heart..."
♪The rusting story, the story hidden in my coat without being sung
♪In exchange for that, I let go of myself many times
♪But in life, "yet" always follows
♪I confess to you, the romance of the sunset glow
♪With the heat of candles in the middle of the story
♪Wishing to the world, turning my back, the last last song
♪The frustration and the future we'll live together
♪～
♪The corners of the book, the scribbles on my chest, still untouched
♪Because I think we haven't even reached the entrance
♪I confess, the romance of departure
♪Your mission is guided by love
♪Become the shoulder on which the birds come to talk
♪With gentle peace, and from now on, we'll live together
♪～